Osgood, Frances Sargent Locke, 1811-1850. Frances Sargent Locke Osgood papers, 1838-1850 (MS Am 1355): Guide.
Frances Sargent Locke Osgood papers,
1838-1850.
Houghton Library, Harvard College Library, Harvard University
MS Am 1355
Osgood, Frances Sargent Locke, 1811-1850.
1 box (.5 linear ft.)
Papers of American poet Frances Sargent Locke Osgood.
54M-222. Gift of Mrs. Arthur W. Fletcher; received: 1955.
There are no restrictions on physical access to this material. Collection is open for research.
Osgood was an American poet.
Arranged alphabetically.
Collection contains personal correspondence, some professional correspondence pertaining to her writings, and manuscripts of her poems. Also clippings of Osgood's work from periodicals, and poems by others addressed to her.
- Anthony, Henry Bowen, 1815-1884. A.L.s. to Frances Sargent (Locke) Osgood; Providence, 4 Mar 1845., (1); 1s.(2p.)
- Barney, John. A.L.s. to [Samuel Stillman] Osgood; Boston, 18 Jan 1844., (2); 1s.(3p.)
- Bartlett, W. O. A.L.s. to [Frances Sargent (Locke)] Osgood; Worcester, 7 Nov 1847., (3); 1s.(3p.)
- Benjamin, Park, 1809-1864. A.L.s. to [same]; [New York] 19 Jan [18--], (4); 1s.(1p.)
- Bill, Margaret. 2 A.L.s. to same:, (5)
  New York, 10 Jun 1841. 1s.(4p.)
  [N.p.] 19 Sep 1845. 1s.(4p.)
- Brooks, Erastus, 1815-1886. 2 A.L.s. to same:, (6)
  New York, 23 Mar [18--] 1s.(1p.)
  Washington, 12 Dec [18--] 1s.(2p.)
- Brown, K. B. 6 A.L.s. to same:, (7)
  [Providence] 2 Jan 1845. 1s.(3p.)
  Same, 21 Feb 1846. 1s.(4p.)
  Same, 20 Jul 1846. 1s.(4p.)
  Same, 1 Dec 1846. 1s.(4p.)
  Same, 10 Mar 1847. 1s.(3p.)
  [Same, n.d.] 1s.(3p.) wants beginning.
- Conrad, Robert Taylor, 1810-1858. A.L.s. to same; Philadelphia, 17 Apr 1848., (8); 1s.(2p.)
- Davidson, Robert, 1808-1876. A.L.s. to same; New Brunswick, 1 Dec 1847., (9); 1s.(4p.)
- Doggett, John. A.L.s. to same; New York, 14 Dec 1846., (10); 1s.(2p.)
- Duyckinck, Evert Augustus, 1816-1879. A.L.s. to same; [New York] 18 Aug 1845., (11); 1s.(1p.)
- Felter, M. A. A.L.s. to [Frances Sargent (Locke) Osgood]; New Baltimore, 23 Jul 1847., (12); 1s.(4p.)
- Fields, James Thomas, 1816-1881. 2 A.L.s. to same:, (13)
  Boston, 10 Oct 1842. 1s.(2p.)
  [Same, n.d.] 1s.(2p.)
- Franklin, Benjamin, 1812-1878. A.L.s. to same; Seneca Falls, 3 Aug 1844., (14); 1s.(4p.)
- Fuller, Hiram, 1815?-1880. 20 A.L.s. to same:, (15)
  Providence, 2 Oct 1842. 1s.(4p.)
  [Same?] 24 Oct 1842. 1s.(4p.)
  Same, 1 Nov 1842. 1s.(4p.)
  [Same] 8 Nov 1842. 1s.(4p.)
  Same, 9 Nov 1842. 1s.(4p.)
  [Same?] 14 Nov [ 1842 ] 1s.(4p.)
  Same, 16 Nov 1842. 1s.(4p.)
  [Same?] 20 Nov 1842. 1s.(4p.)
  [Same?] 21 Nov 1842. 1s.(4p.)
  [Same?] 10 Dec 1842. 1s.(4p.)
  [Same?] 21 Dec 1842. 1s.(4p.)
  [Same?] 6 Jan 1843. 1s.(4p.)
  Same, 15 Jan 1843. 1s.(4p.)
  [Same?] 18 Jan 1843. 1s.(2p.)
  [Same?] 22 Jan 1843. 1s.(4p.)
  [Same?] 10 Feb 1843. 1s.(4p.)
  Same, 27 Feb 1843. 1s.(4p.)
  Same, 13 Mar 1843. 1s.(4p.)
  Same, 5 Apr 1843. 1s.(4p.)
  New York, 24 Jul 1845. 1s.(2p.)
  [N.p.,n.d.] 1s.(2p.)
- Gillespie, William Mitchell, 1816-1868. 3 A.L.s. to same:, (16)
  [Schenectady] 14 May 1845. 1s.(4p.)
  [Same] 6 May 1846. 1s.(4p.)
  New York, 29 Dec [18--] 1s.(4p.)
- Gleason, F. A.L.s. to same; Boston, 9 Feb 1849., (17); 1s.(1p.)
- Graham, George Rex, 1813-1894. 4 A.L.s. to same:, (18)
  [Philadelphia] 24 Jan 1845. 1s.(3p.)
  [Same, 20 Sep 1845? ] 1s.(2p.)
  [Same, 9 Oct 1845? ] 1s.(3p.)
  Same, 28 Oct 1845. 1s.(1p.)
- Gray, William. A.L.s. to Frances Sargent (Locke) Osgood; [n.p.] 6 Apr 1844., (19); 1s.(1p.)
- Griswold, Rufus Wilmot, 1815-1857. [Agreement with George Palmer Putnam to edit and publish "The memorial," 1850] A.MS.s.; New York, 23 Sep 1850., (20); 1s.(1p.)
- Halgard, E. H. A.L.s. to Frances Sargent (Locke) Osgood; Providence, 14 May 1845., (21); 1s.(3p.)
- Harrington, Eliza R. A.L.s. to same; [n.p.,n.d.], (22); 1s.(3p.)
- Hillard, H. L. 3 A.L.s. to same:, (23)
  Brooklyn, 8 Oct 1839. 1s.(4p.)
  London, 27 Feb 1840. 1s.(4p.)
  Croydon, 2 Aug 1840. 2s.(8p.)
- Hoffman, Charles Fenno, 1806-1884. A.L.s. to same; [n.p.,n.d.], (24); 1s.(2p.)
- Hoppin, James Mason, 1820-1906. A.L.s. to same; [n.p.,n.d.], (25); 1s.(2p.)
- Jenks, Harriet N. A.L.s. to same; Boston, 13 Feb 1843., (26); 1s.(4p.)
- Labree, Lawrence. 2 A.L.s. to same:, (27)
  New York, 13 Nov 1846. 1s.(4p.)
  Same, 16 Dec 1846. 1s.(3p.)
- Oaksmith, E. A.L.s. to same; [n.p.,n.d.], (28); 1s.(3p.)
- Osgood, Frances Sargent (Locke) 1811-1850. A.L.s. to Charles A. Locke; Brooklyn [n.d.], (29); 1s.(2p.)
- Osgood, Frances Sargent (Locke) 1811-1850. A.L.s. to Anna Q. T. Parsons; [Hingham, 15 Oct 18--], (30); 1s.(4p.)
- Osgood, Frances Sargent (Locke) 1811-1850. A.L. (wants ending) to [Charles Jacobs] Peterson; [n.p.,n.d.], (31); 1s.(2p.)
- Osgood, Frances Sargent (Locke) 1811-1850. [Power of attorney to Rufus Wilmot Griswold] MS. (in Griswold's autograph) s.; New York, 19 Mar 1849., (32); 1.(1p.)
- Osgood, Frances Sargent (Locke) 1811-1850. MS.L.(possibly from Clark Austin, publishers; wants ending); New York, 20 Jun 1845., (33); 1s.(2p.)
  Proposed terms for publishing Mrs Osgood's poems.
- Osgood, Samuel Stillman. A.L.s. to [Rufus Wilmot] Griswold; Boston, 13 Jul 1850., (34)
- Osgood, Samuel Stillman. 3 A.L.s. to Frances Sargent (Locke) Osgood:, (35)
  Boston, 17 Apr 1844. 1s.(4p.)
  New Brunswick, 6 Jul 1847. 1s.(4p.)
  Same, 5 Aug 1847. 1s.(4p.)
- Parsons, Anna Q. T. 5 A.L.s. to Frances Sargent (Locke) Osgood:, (36)
  Weston, 21 Aug 1839. 1s.(4p.)
  Groton, 2 Sep 1841. 1s.(4p.)
  Boston, 23 Jul 1843. 1s.(4p.)
  [N.p.,n.d.] 1s.(3p.)
  [N.p.,n.d.] 1s.(4p.)
- Payne, Abraham, 1818-1886. A.L.s. to same; Providence, 25 Dec 1845., (37); 1s.(3p.)
- Peterson, Charles Jacobs, 1819-1887. A.L.s. to same; [Philadelphia, 1 Jun 18--], (38); 1s.(3p.)
- Raymond, Henry Jarvis, 1820-1869. A.L.s. to same; [n.p.] 24 Feb [18--], (39); 1s.(3p.)
- Sargent, Epes, 1813-1880. A.L.s. to same; [New York] 13 Dec 1842., (40); 1s.(1p.)
- Snelling, Anna L. A.L.s. to same; New York, 18 Dec 1842., (41); 1s.(2p.)
- Sully, Blanche. A.L.s. to same; Philadelphia, 7 Oct [1838], (42); 1s.(4p.)
- Thaxter, L. L. A.L.s. to same; Isles of Shoals, 29 Mar 1848., (43); 1s.(4p.)
- Thomas, E. I. A.L.s. to same; Birmingham, 18 Nov 1843., (44); 1s.(4p.)
- Warren, Owen Grenliffe. A.L.s. to Frances Sargent (Locke) Osgood; New York 20 Jun 1847., (45); 1s.(4p.)
- Welford, Charles. 4 A.L.s. to same:, (46)
  London, 3 Feb 1846. 1s.(4p.)
  New York, 23 Dec [18--] 1s.(3p.)
- Wells, Anna Maria (Foster) 1795?-1868. A.L.s. to Park Benjamin; Providence, 20 Jun 1842., (47); 1s.(1p.)
- Wells, William Vincent, 1826-1876. 2 A.L.s. to Frances Sargent (Locke) Osgood:, (48)
  Boston, 9 Jun 1844. 1s.(4p.)
  Antwerp, 22 Nov 1845. 1s.(4p.)
- Willis, Mary. A.L.s. to same; [n.p.,n.d.], (49); 1s.(3p.)
- Osgood, Frances Sargent (Locke) 1811-1850, recipient. 23 letters from various unidentified correspondents., (50)
- Osgood, Frances Sargent (Locke) 1811-1850. [Literary MSS.], (51); 46 pieces.
- Osgood, Frances Sargent (Locke) 1811-1850. [Cuttings of periodical publications of her works]., (52); 1 folder.
- [Compositions by various hands, mainly addressed to Frances Sargent (Locke) Osgood], (53); 22 pieces.
  Last poem is by Bayard Taylor, see also bMS Am 1598 (420-421).